Sebastian Daza

Social data scientist and demographer with more than 10 years of experience in managing, designing, supervising, and analyzing applied and academic social studies. Strong quantitative-qualitative skills and theoretical background. Eager to apply my knowledge and skills to solve social problems and work with interdisciplinary teams.

Skills

- o Data Science: Machine and Deep Learning, NLP, Visualization (Dash, Shiny), SQL.
- Modeling: Proficiency and experience in statistical and demographic techniques (GLM, multilevel models, SNA, SEM, survival analysis, causal inference, Bayesian statistics). Agent-Based Modeling (ABM) and Simulation. See working papers on my website.
- **Research**: Designed, analyzed and presented research in academic conferences applied and academic research projects on social inequality, education, social psychology, adolescent behaviors, and social networks.
- Survey Research: Experience designing and implementing questionnaires using different modes (in-person, phone, web), sampling and analysis adjustments (weights, missing data). Created R package sampler for practitioners.
- **Project Management**: Led more than 20 research national and international projects, teams of 40 people, and manage an annual budget of US\$400,000.
- o **Software**: Statistics: R, Stata, Mplus, HLM, SPSS, SAS, CTM, Stan, INLA. Qualitative software: Nvivo. Data entry and processing: CSPro. Social Network: Ucinet, R-Siena. Agent-based modeling (ABM) and System Dynamics: Anylogic, Netlogo.
- o **Programming**: Python, Java (basic).
- o Languages: English (fluent) and Spanish (native).

Professional Experience

Research Assistant

University of Wisconsin-Madison

July 2012-current

Participated in four research projects resulting in 5 working papers under review to be published.

R Package Developer

Applied Population Laboratory (APL), UW-Madison

2014-current

Created R package acsr to help extract variables and statistics using the America Community Survey and Decennial US Census.

Methodology Consultant

Center for Social Studies (DESUC), Catholic University of Chile

August 2010-current

Designed sampling and post-adjustments in nationally representative studies in Chile. Provided methodological guidance (attrition, non-response adjustments).

Project Manager

Center for Social Studies (DESUC), Catholic University of Chile

May 2005-July 2010

Led research projects in areas such social cohesion, political perception and government approval ratings, education, crime and delinquency, and organizational studies.

Lecturer

Catholic University of Chile

2008–2009

Taught courses on advanced methods for social research, qualitative analysis, and design and implementation of social surveys.

Education

Ph.D. Candidate (ABD) in Sociology and Demography

University of Wisconsin-Madison, US

2010-present

Fellow

The Data Incubator, US

2017

Master of Arts in Sociology

Catholic University, Chile

2009

Bachelor of Arts in Sociology

Catholic University, Chile

2004